Blue **Pilkinton-Ching**

bluepilkintonching@gmail.com **Games Portfolio** Linkedin Github

ABOUT ME

Since the age of ten or eleven, I have been programming. I started with scratch, the visual block-based programming language, and since then have gone to develop games and web apps, both independently and in groups of teams. I love to learn, and get a kick out of building interactive and practical products. Solving problems is my specialty! I thrive on jumping into a challenge and devising creative solutions for it. I am also very passionate and curious about the possibilities of tech, recently I have been developing a web app for interfacing with GPT models.

With my most recent study at Dev Academy, alongside the development of technical skills there has been a very strong emphasis on Human Skills when working in teams. I'm all for it! I have a strong value for kindness, empathy, and communication. Any place I work at, or situation I'm in, I strive for inclusivity and diversity.

SKILLS

Primary

- Fullstack web development
- Javascript, Typescript
- Game development with Unity Engine
- Git

Secondary

- Unreal Engine
- 3d modeling, rendering and animating with Maya
- Texturing with Substance Painter
- Video Editing
- Photoshop

DIGITAL PROJECTS

I have worked on numerous digital projects related to web development, and the Unity Game Engine. Recently, through my bootcamp course at Dev Academy, I have worked independently and in teams to produce web apps that involve:

- Authentication
- **REST API calls**
- **Databases**
- React
- Test Driven Development
- Node.js
- Linux
- **Typescript**
- Many different libraries including Express, Handlebars, Knex and more!

Some of the games I have made have involved:

rea

I have participated in several game Jams in the past including KiwiJam, and Game Jam Aotearoa. I have also created many of which can be found on my instagram portfolio or github

EDUCATION

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Wellington

AUG 2023 - DEC 2023

• Level 6 certificate in Applied Software Development

EXPERIENCE

Dev Academy Aotearoa, Wellington

AUG 2023 - DEC 2023

Dev Academy has done an outstanding job at simulating an agile team environment very similar to how many tech companies operate. At Dev Academy, I've utilized soft skills to work with groups with 2 - 6 people to develop original web apps.

Adrenalin Forest, Porirua - Staff Member

JAN 2023 - PRESENT

Adrenalin Forest is a high ropes course outdoors attraction. My role involves briefing customers, supervising climbers, and performing rescues on the courses if people get stuck.

Backyard Cafe, Palmers Garden Center - Front of House

DEC 2020 - JAN 2023

I worked as a staff member of the Backyard Cafe front of house team. My role included basic food prep, waitering, and serving customers at the till.

Yoobee College of Creative Innovation, Wellington

JULY 2022 - JUNE 2023

• Level 5 diploma in Animation

Aotea College, Porirua

FEB 2018 - JULY 2022

- NCEA Level 1 with Overall Excellence
- NCEA Level 2 with Overall Excellence
- NCEA Level 3 Achieved (within 6 months)
- 2020 Plimmerton Rotary Award for 'Service above Self'

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST